all right everybody thanks for joining
me it's the first time I've done a
periscope like this I have been doing
the periscopes on my college tour but I
wanted to just get some information out
to you I was I was driving back with red
hen from Charlottesville from UVA where
we were down there and I was given a
speech to the College Republicans that
went really well is all about the
Democrats of the plural buck and my
transition to a deplorable Trump voter
from the Democratic Party and the crowd
was great the energy was really high and
we had a fantastic time
and all the way back you know we put on
a couple podcasts thanks Jenna we put on
a couple of podcasts to pass the time
and we were listening to Dave Rubin
and the first one that we listened to
from Dave was talk of Carlson and that
guy was great that was fantastic I love
listening to him I can listen to him
anytime but the the second one we
listened to Dave Dave Rubin had on a
woman who was so called anti feminist
who has a PhD in FEM and you know Gender
Studies and feminism and she teaches in
in Ottawa and she was going on very
accurately about how feminism is anti
masculine and there are all of these
symptoms out there in today's culture
that are showing men falling behind and
how feminism is attacking men and making
them feel somehow inadequate and that
their unwanted by their culture in their
society and both she and Dave referenced
Jordan Peterson as somebody who is
tackling this issue and getting out
there and talking to thousands of people
about how men especially young men who
are feeling lost in today's society can
can find their way and what they can do
it in order to improve themselves and
you know what I what struck me was that
listening to Jordan Peterson I know that
like one of the main things that he
wants you know people to do is to clean
up their room and to get their act
together
and to start you know being productive
you know in their own lives and to
really take care of themselves before
they they move forward but beyond that I
don't think Jordan Pearson necessarily
has the prescriptive ideas that are
gonna help men rise up and and take
responsibility for themselves and take
responsibility for their life and find a
way to create a life that is going to be
fruitful and be pleasurable and be you
know of utility to society and you know
I've listened to Jordan Pearson for a
long time and I really respect the guy
and his early podcast with Joe Rogan was
was really an eye-opener for a lot of
people and you know I think we're all
indebted to him for spreading the
message but what I'm finding with him is
that there's a the bridge to an actual
solution to these problems is hard to
find and I don't think he necessarily
has the answer and listening to this
woman listening to Dave go on about how
all these issues are there for men and
how feminism is really degrading
masculinity they were sort of missing
you know the the main point in the link
to how we're going to solve this problem
and you know I think it's kind of
surprising to me that feminists are
surprised that there is a rising anti
ideology to what they're pushing forth
and what we've seen over the last 10
years in the vari for darkest corners
and furthest reaches of the Internet has
been a bubbling up of a men's movement
that's not and I'm not talking about men
going their own way or men's right
advocates or anything like that I'm
talking about men getting together and
helping each other find a way in this
new environment that is completely
shaped by feminism the feminine
imperative and you know culminating in
what we saw just recently with the
Cavanagh hearings where we're now
completely throwing out due process or
completely throwing out the notion that
were innocent until proven guilty and is
all culmination of events that have been
building up and and came through
relationships and and through the
universities and now found its way all
the way to the Supreme Court so for us
to to acknowledge
what to do them before we have to come
up with an antidote and the first thing
to do is to accept that there's a
problem and there is a there is a
problem and it's now it's now left you
know men's forums and old pickup artist
forums and and issues around
relationships and it's now made its way
all the way to the Supreme Court so the
the feminists and radical feminist
movement has created an environment in
which we need to have an answer and an
antidote and I've been participating in
you know the underground sort of men's
movement for a number of years my
initial writing is at Jack Murphy live
where Jack Murphy live.com we're all
about relationships and we're all about
male-female dynamics and then I began to
understand the philosophies behind them
all I began to understand how feminism
was degrading men and that because
feminism believes that all cultures have
been patriarchal and patriarchy is
oppressive and the only way to to free
women is to attack and degrade
masculinity we're now seeing that taking
place and the the men's movement that
I've been a part of is starting to
bubble up to the surface and I recently
went to this convention in Florida
called the 21 convention and there were
about 300 people there all men there was
a number of speakers maybe 20 25
speakers who all spoke on various issues
of men men's related to men and men's
issues men's development whether it's
Fitness fashion mindset how to be red
pill in a blue pill world how to manage
your relationships how to make money how
to pick a wife how to establish a great
relationship all these issues were being
discussed with hundreds of men who had
come together for four days in Florida
who had spent you know some guys spend a
couple of grand to come down to this
conference and these are not losers
these are guys with money and these are
guys with jobs this conference has been
going on for a number of years and these
guys have already improved themselves
they were guys that were a fit who were
stylish and they all wanted to come
together and commune with other
masculine men or
getting to find a way to navigate this
world that is being dominated currently
by radical feminism and what struck me
at the end not only was the Avengers
tremendous the camaraderie the the the
Brotherhood the information but at the
end of the event
the New York Times sent a reporter down
there and she wanted to write a her name
is Nellie Bowles and she was the one who
wrote the hit piece on Jordan Peterson
back in May he she came down there and
crashed our event and we we knew that
she wanted to talk to us and we were
going to set up a very structure and
approach for her to engage with the
speakers for her to engage with our
content we had a whole interview room
set up we were gonna do all of the
interviews live on camera so that there
was no question as to what was said or
what the content was you know we were
really gonna you know handle our media
the way that we were meant to and I was
appointed media contact for the
convention and so when she crashed our
event I reached out to her and I took
her side and I talked to her and
explained why she couldn't just show up
at our at our party and just start
talking to people and how we were gonna
control the message she was really
surprised at how organized that we were
and she was really surprised at how
media savvy we were and she was also
really surprised I think the fact I told
her that we didn't really need her you
know we have our own ways of getting the
message out we have our own way of
transmitting information we built an
infrastructure we've built a network of
blogs and Twitter feeds and YouTube
channels and email lists and we've
learned this media game over the last
four or five years to the point where we
don't even need the New York Times and
she was really struck by that and she
actually just left like she completely
skipped out and didn't even take time to
to interview anybody because you know
she realized she wasn't gonna be able to
do a sneak attack on us and so what this
told me in conjunction with listening to
Dave Rubin and this this female academic
and her 50s you know talk about
radical feminism and the progressive
left and this hate machine that they
built listening to talk about what it
wants to answer how are we going to help
men how are men going to find their way
in today's world where the message that
everybody is sending them is that
they're you know unwanted that there are
oppressors that they have to they have
to repent for the sins of a thousand
years of patriarchy all today at this
very moment I'm listening to this and
and I realize that Dave Rubin doesn't
have the answer this feminist woman
doesn't have the answer Jordan Peterson
doesn't have the answer
it's our men's movement that has the
answer our men's movement is a dedicated
group of guys who have worked together
to advance methods and mind frames and
and concepts and structured plans of
development of improving our masculine
selves and learning how to navigate this
world that we find ourselves in today
and the mainstream media is starting to
pick up on it okay the New York Times
wants to write a big expose about us she
said that we're having this tremendous
impact on people and that is very true
there were guys at the conference like
rich Cooper who reached hundreds of
thousands of people out there we've got
Rollo Tomassi who sold tens of thousands
of books he's the Godfather of the red
pill and what some people would call the
manosphere ed Lattimore was there AJ
Cortez Alexander Cortez was there hunter
Drew was there who had built the
fraternity of excellence with his guys
there was just a whole list of guys that
were there doing positive things all Pro
masculine completely respectful of women
and that they're in right there is the
answer and I'm realizing right now that
this moment in time this year wrapping
up moving into 2019 this is the moment
at which the men's movement that I've
been a part of for a decade that I've
written about and participated in a bit
a leader in is about ready to explode
into the mainstream because not only are
they picking up on the fact that we're
having influence not only are we they
picking up on the fact that we've been
around and we've developed these
networks but now also guys in our
network like
you know sort of in our sphere like
they've reuben and whatnot are now
asking for the answers there they're
finally now something that there's a
problem you know five years ago if you
said the feminism was a problem for you
for men today people would have sort of
laughed at you but now it's becoming and
then it's the Cavanaugh the Cavanaugh
hearings are what has really brought
this to the forefront I think and
crystallized everything for both the men
and the women that don't believe in this
radical feminism we've now seen that
this is something that's bubbling up all
the way to the highest highest pour you
know parts of our country to the Supreme
Court and it's now time for us to for
the answer to be sought and the
counter-argument to feminism and the
counter argument to an ideology that
desperately wants to destroy the root of
patriarchal power which is masculinity
the antidote to that is teaching men how
to be men again and you know Jordan
Peterson is filling it's filling the
these rooms all across the world
actually decided European tour where
there's just thousands of young men who
are reaching out to him and asking him
what to do and he's telling them to
clean their room but you know what you
know there's a lot more to it than that
and there's a lot more depth to it and
jordan peterson hasn't been a part of
our culture our little men's culture for
ten years Jorn peterson has been living
his academic life say anything bad about
it but he hasn't been in the trenches he
hasn't been actually down there helping
guys in developing this thought process
these in this mind frame and the mindset
that is necessary in order to run
counterbalance to what's happening out
there and so I'm seeing right now I'm
driving in the car coming back from
speaking at UVA on political issues
right I started writing about men's
issues and relationships and now I'm
writing about politics and I'm writing
about culture and I've got a very
successful book Democrats are deplorable
and it's gaining popularity and gaining
speed I'm going to Columbia University
I'm going to speak at Ivy Lee
I'm going to University of New Mexico
I'm going to Evergreen State College to
bring this political message which is a
unifying theory that tells us that
what's disrupting our relationships and
what's disrupting men today and boys and
giving them a sense of hopelessness
stretches all the way through our
political cultural institutions all the
way up until the Supreme Court all the
way up into the highest portions of our
government all the way up to the
presidency and now I'm out there talking
about Democrats in the floor bow which
builds on all these issues but then at
the same time I'm after 21 convention
still hanging out with my boys still you
know attached to my roots still doing
the work with men that brought me to
this understanding in the first place
and I realize that I am sort of one of
the first people that's able to both
disband both worlds I'm able to
participate in the men's community what
it used to be called the manosphere or
red pill or whatever you want to call it
participate in that but have the
intellectual capabilities the media
savvy
the communication skills and the fighter
spirit frankly to bring that message
also to the mainstream and I'm out there
already talking to people in the
mainstream I'm already out there talking
to universities to just regular people
in their classrooms and their lecture
calls and no one else from my community
is doing that so I realized Dave Rubin
is asking for answers Jordan Peterson is
failing and giving the answers there's
this feminist professor you know from
Ottawa who's got she tells me that her
tells Dave in their interview that she
gets emails thousands of emails from
boys asking her to help them and you
know no offense but a
a 55 year old feminist professor who's
seen the light isn't the right person to
teach a 22 year old man how to really
grow up and become a full version of
himself that he and achieve the vision
that he wants to become you know that's
me but I have I have the answers and you
know I'm not saying this to brag but
like I have gone through the process of
change and transformation I've done the
research I've done the writing
I'm interacted and engaged with these
kind of men all over the country I've
speaking in men's conferences I'm
talking to other leaders in the sphere
and I'm also very involved in the
political aspect and I'm also involved
in be the person that is bridging this
gap between this emerging man's movement
and and using that as an answer to
solving the problems that we're facing
in our culture today that culminated in
this cabinet hearings it is crazy what I
saw with Cavanaugh where the notion that
we must believe all women no matter what
they say that the feminine imperative is
the most important thing that we've got
going on we have to adhere to it at all
times and that you can just cast aside a
man with a whole lifetime of work just
because a woman said something about
something that happened allegedly 35
years ago that was uncorroborated
unsubstantiated and refuted by every
witness that she named so a few years
ago if you would have asked me if I
would have thought that the men's
movement by started with started writing
with that I'm a part of still proudly to
this day was going to find its way into
the mainstream political discourse was
gonna find its way into the Supreme
Court I would have thought that you were
crazy
but there's no question that that's the
case today there's no question that
everywhere I go there are young men who
feel like they don't have a proper
masculine role models they're young out
there there are young men out there who
don't understand how to become the best
version of themselves none of these guys
I saw
either at any of the colleges I've been
to have really you know built themselves
out or had a strong secure vision of
their future and how they were gonna
navigate this world you know I got a
question last night from one of the kids
in the audience when the young men in
the audience he said how do we how do we
tell people that just because we're men
and just because we are Republicans that
were not racist or sexist and you know
that that really struck me because he
was sincere and his question and he felt
ostracized just by the sake of being a
man and you know in my book I explained
how the college campuses starting with
orientation the class structure the
communication standards and norms of
biased response teams the title nine the
sexual harassment policies I explained
how all of that is rooted in radical
feminism and how it's changing and
shaping every kid that goes through
walks through the door of a university
or college in America today and then I
also explain how every all those people
graduate college get hired by these you
know institutions and professional
organizations who then adapt to their
expectations and so radical feminism's
thinking has really just blasted through
from the from the universities into our
HR departments our corporations our
institutions our government institutions
all the way up to the Supreme Court so
I'm realizing right now that this is the
moment this is the moment at which
everything I've been working for for the
last ten years everything I've been
writing everything I've been talking
about all the guys I've been talking to
this whole thing I've been a part of
both men's and masculinity issues and
the sort of Mogga
you know how do we fight back against
radical feminism and Hillary Clinton
being you know sort of the avatar for a
radical feminism how all that is now
coming together and I'm realizing that
this is the moment this is the moment
where it all becomes real and you know
I've done good to establish you know my
presence and media done well to
establish myself as a writer and a
thinker
and the the time is now the time is now
and I'm ready to seize the moment the
the country is ready to receive these
messages young men across the country
are starving for this information and
our talking heads out there like Dave
Rubin are beginning to really
acknowledge the fact and in fact he even
called it the beginning of a new culture
war sort of the rise of masculinity that
the rebirth of masculinity our Talking
Heads are starting to talk about it and
people are asking what do we do and how
do we do it and you know that we have
the answers in our in our little corner
of the internet and in my writings and
the writings of many other people and
we're about ready to bust out into the
national narrative and I'm really
excited for it and I'm just thankful for
everybody who's been a part of it so far
and I want you guys to all stick around
I want you to follow me on Twitter at
Jack Murphy live I want you to go to my
website Jack Murphy live.com sign up to
my email list look for big things coming
by the book Democrats are deplorable
which explains all this stuff you know I
cited guys in you know writers from the
men's world in my book and to give us
context and to begin giving building a
body of literature that is meant to
compete and counteract this narrative
from radical feminism that's that's not
just crazy blue haired people freaking
out on campus anymore it's all the way
to the Supreme Court of the United
States of America this issue is real
it's everywhere it affects all of us
and it's not going away and it's only
going to get worse and without a
sufficient force pushing back against
the radical feminists and against
intersectional lists and against the
critical social thinking and against all
this nonsense it's coming from the
universities which is now everywhere in
our country it's only gonna get worse
and and we need the answer and the
answer is here and the answer can be
found with the guys that we're at the 21
convention the answer can be found with
me the answer can be found with the guys
that I run with and the answer is gonna
be found and a lot of the media and the
10th that I'm gonna be putting out in
the future you need to branch out to
high schools you know what's funny is I
love working with kids and I love
working with people and I love working
with men not only do I have coaching
clients where I help guys you know
achieve their vision of themselves and
to make themselves better but I also
coach Little League boys for five years
helping them become better men and
helping them learn about camaraderie and
teamwork and discipline and leadership
and because of who I am I got the hand
from coaching Little League okay I got
banned from coaching Little League after
I got doxxed I got fired
I had the cop sent to my house I had my
name and reputation destroyed
and I'm fighting back and I've had
enough of it and I'm sick of it and I'm
gonna be a model for people and I'm
going to be a leader for people I
already am and I'm just gonna keep
fighting yeah
have I spoke to Dave Rubin about it yet
Dave Rubin and I have talked a number of
times he's told me he wants to get me on
the show at least like three times
everybody on Twitter was calling him out
asking him you know to get me on the
show he and I have had a number of
personal conversations about it but you
know dude is busy and he's got guys like
Tucker Carlson coming on the show and
Larry King and stuff but I know he needs
to have me on the show Dave Rubin you
need to have me on the show because you
need you you're on the cusp man you're
on the verge you figured out what the
problems are you've identified all the
issues you've identified the negative
consequences of what's happening but you
haven't had anyone on your show that can
tell people what to do to make it better
and you haven't had anyone on the show
who has been fighting these fights for
ten years now and it's time that you
have somebody on the show like that Dave
so Dave quit screwing around Jordan
Peterson and get Jack Murphy live on the
show because this is going to be the
story of 2019 Nellie Bowles in The New
York Times I already know it's gonna be
the story of 2019 they're trying to
already bring this subculture to the
forefront
I've got writers from various mainstream
organization
already talking to me you know trying to
work on getting a profile done you know
on big radio shows and big well-known
publications so it's out there the the
sense that this is important is out
there the sense that the time is now is
out there and I just was so pumped up
listening to this podcast on the way
home from Charlottesville after my talk
at UVA that you know I decided to come
back and do my very first periscope so
you know I apologize and setup is pretty
sparse
I had my Democrats of the plural sign
behind me but then I saw that it was the
image was reversed so I'm gonna have to
figure that out we have to get a new
camera and a new stuff up and all that
but you know the time is now guys and I
appreciate all the support that you've
shown me so far I appreciate all the
amazing emails do you guys send guys
send me messages saying that I've saved
their lives wife send me the pic
by said messages saying that you know my
writing has helped them in their
relationships I've got a great group of
donors people have supported my travels
they donated me money quietly people are
offering me money people are offering to
help fund my college tour and it's
really just an amazing groundswell of
support and I think part of it comes
from the fact that I got doxxed by an
Tifa they fired I got fired from my job
I got swatted BAM from coaching Little
League and I didn't roll over man
there's no way I'm gonna roll over you
know I'm a fighter I'm gonna fight back
and I'm not gonna take this laying down
LaCie McCauley tried to try to strike me
down that and Tifa chick she tried to
strike me down and I don't know wait
watch this blocked that's she tried to
tried to strike me down and you know
funny thing I came back even stronger
than before and I'm gonna come back even
stronger and momentum is building and
you guys are awesome
and this periscope stuff is awesome I'm
gonna keep doing it does the book detail
what happened to you
no because I was writing the book while
it all happened and so there were
sort of red pilling moments and you know
moments of transformation that happened
to me prior to that and I talk about
those in the book but what just happened
to me where I got doxxed and whatnot no
that that wasn't in there and and I'm
realizing that I haven't been telling
that story enough I feel like I'm
talking about it all the time but I
gotta keep talking about it because
people don't really realize like the
treachery of the progressive left yeah
red head says you can read the story on
my blog at Jack Murphy live.com so I'm
gonna keep fighting and I'm gonna keep
pushing on and I'm just excited because
this is a moment right now you know the
21 convention and I got a really hand it
to Anthony Johnson
Anthony dream Johnson he put together an
amazing event guys an amazing event
where there were almost 300 people and
it was incredibly professionally well
done
and I can't wait for all the content for
that to come out but it was really
inspiring to me and to everyone who was
there and when the New York Times
reporter showed up at the end and and
and told us that this is this is her new
you know expose she's working on it
really it's really all coalesce for me
in the last few days and giving me a
clear sense of vision and a clear sense
of mission which is pretty much the
number one message that I want guys to
get is that they need to have a sense of
mission and they need to put that
mission first and they need to put their
physical health and their emotional
health and their spiritual health first
and not in a selfish way but in a way
that empowers them to be useful to both
themselves their family their community
and then hopefully to the rest of their
nation mark New York Times trying to be
fake news and smear all of us yeah of
course of course that's what they want
because even though Nellie says to me
she says well the New York Times is
interested in covering all aspects of
gender now you know we we know that's a
joke we saw we saw what she wrote about
Jordan Peterson and you know we know who
the New York Times is hired they hire
open open racists open sexist people who
have complete disdain for white men for
white guy and say kill all the white
guys etc etc so we know what the New
York Times is all about and we know what
the mainstream media is all about and we
we have to fight that we have to push
back and really I don't want to be
dramatic but nothing less than the fate
of our nation depends on whether or not
we're gonna be able to have a rebirth of
masculinity in this country of a
positive masculinity of a masculinity
that leads and guides and shapes and
achieves and creates and takes care of
themselves their family their community
in their nation this is what I'm talking
about I'm not talking about brochette
I'm not talking about you know going
around macking on girls all the time I'm
talking about how how to control
yourself how to control your emotions
how to control your life how to fight
back from adversity the talk I gave at
the 21 convention was called you know
mastering the art of the comeback
because that's something that I've had
to do these are the kind of messages we
need to get out you think our country is
needing this I mean I don't know if you
follow me or not but like or the news or
anything else out there but yeah the
country needs it a hundred percent it
all all this has culminated in the
cabinet hearings where we see the power
of radical feminism saying we need to
believe all women just because they're
women okay they're saying that the truth
objective reality is about what a woman
says that should be terrifying for
everyone because that means that the
rule of law is done that means that
evidence is done that means that we're
on the verge of like a reign of terror
where all it takes is an accusation and
a smear and you are done you are
finished and I have lived this you know
you think you think it might be crazy to
say this stuff but like the woman
accused me of being a alright Nazi and
what do you know I get fired a month
later like even despite of all of the
evidence even despite of the facts you
have to believe all women is the new
mantra so of course this country needs
it and it's not just me saying that it
we have the symptoms are out there men
aren't going to college as much as women
anymore men are falling behind in there
thank you more appreciated men are
falling behind in
academically professionally therefore I
mind the health is worse they're killing
themselves at a higher rate than women
this is pure two women need to
stop this nonsense yeah I agree with
that and so the evidence is out there
and the rooms that Jordan Peterson fills
with thousands of people in every city
across the country and all over Europe
was a thousand boys all trying to figure
out how do I make myself into a man and
unfortunately the only advice that that
married guy has you know who's been in
marriage forever the only advice that he
has is to is to clean your room now I
know there's a little bit more to it
than that but he doesn't have the answer
and he's not as connected to the young
people of America as I am and he's not
connected in the way that some of my
other compadres and the man you know
men's development world are and so we're
the guys with the answer we're the guys
have been developing the stuff on the
ground through trial and error frankly
through trial and error and and
exploring it personally and trying to
make it happen for our own and so this
is the moment guys this is the moment
right here this is the moment where
men's development community meets
radical feminism the Supreme Court
Kavanagh hearings it all comes together
in this moment at 2019 where we're we go
mainstream and where I go mainstream
with this message and we begin the
process of developing a positive
masculinity that's gonna fight back and
that is gonna bring us hopefully back
from the break from the direction that
we're heading I mean haven't haven't you
guys seen the trajectory that we're on
it's not getting any better
you know radical feminism has permanent
permeated every element of our life and
it's so common the thinking the thought
process now that it doesn't even seem
strange anymore it's just widely
accepted and this this trajectory is not
going to slow down unless somebody puts
up a fight now the whole entire premise
of feminism and radical feminism these
days is to destroy masculinity because
masculinity
is the basis for masculine power and
masculine power to the rub to feminists
is the basis for the patriarchy and the
patriarchy is oppressive and women are
oppressed right so that's their thought
process so of course they have to attack
masculinity and they've done a very good
job of it they've done a very good job
of it you know it doesn't take much
observation to see that men in our world
today especially our 20s and 30s
something our millennial guys are are
suffering are suffering and they don't
know they don't know how to become men
and the radical feminism has been
successful enough in extinguishing the
weak and smothering them and the only
men that are left are the men with the
Constitution for revolution the men with
the strength enough to fight back those
are the people who are gonna be leading
the way those are the people that are
going to be pushing the thoughts and
ideas that are going to be the necessary
counterweights
to these ideas these radical ideas which
have now taken over and dominated our
infrastructure our education system our
academia all the way up to the frickin
Supreme Court so that's my rant for
today guys I'm going to hopefully be
doing a lot more a lot more of the
periscopes here and pushing out a lot
more content you know I get hyped about
issues all the time and then because I'm
more of a writer you know I get bogged
down and like really trying to write
things out and write a big essay and all
that but I'm gonna just keep keep
ranting on periscope for a little bit
and see how that goes so thanks
everybody I appreciate all the comments
I appreciate all the hearts follow me on
Twitter if you don't already Jack Murphy
live go to my website Jack Murphy
live.com buy the book
Democrats is deplorable thank you all
for your support and I will see you guys
the next time